Keita Hiyama, aged 35.
緋山啓太，35歲
He's accused of homicide.
被控殺人罪
The victim was murdered at his residence adjacent to Hanegi Seiko.
被害人在和羽木精工廠房 相鄰的住家內遭人謀殺
Your Honor,
庭上
We've been searching for this for a long time.
這是本案中一直找不到的…
It's the murder weapon.
凶器
But that hammer is mine--
但那支鐵鎚是我的…
Mr. Hiyama.
緋山先生
Before the incident,
你在案發之前
did you happen to misplace the hammer?
是不是在哪弄丟了那把鐵鎚？
You walked into the shop empty-handed,
以“覺得很熱，想乘涼”為理由
seeking "to cool off from the heat."
你雙手空空地走進店裡
You pulled out a bag from your front pants pocket,
從褲子前面的口袋取出袋子
placed a pillow inside, and attempted to exit the shop.
把枕頭放進去後就想離開店裡
You entered the shop intending to steal, didn't you?
你一開始就是想偷東西 才進去店裡的吧？
Given these facts,
如上述例證所示
it's clear that the theft of the pillow was deliberate rather than impulsive.
被告人並非臨時起意 而是預謀偷竊枕頭，這點很明顯
It can't be denied the crime was malicious with the potential for repetition.
相當惡劣，而且無法否定 不會有再犯的可能性
That is all.
我說完了
Defense counsel, do you wish to conduct a redirect examination?
辯護人，是否要進行最終詢問？
I, Shinomiya, the defense counsel, will ask another question.
辯護人的紫之宮再次提問
The bag you carried,
那個袋子
wasn't it of personal significance to you?
對你來說很重要吧？
Hyperventilation syndrome.
過度換氣症候群
Three months ago,
你在三個月前
you collapsed at Setagaya-Daita Station on the Odakyu Line.
曾經在小田急線 世田谷代田站內昏倒吧
That's absurd.
太荒謬了
I present evidence number 12, as requested by the defense counsel.
容我出示辯護人請求證據第12號證據
It's a diagnosis of the accused by psychosomatic medicine.
被告人在精神內科的診斷證明書
After the accused collapsed due to hyperventilation syndrome,
被告人自從因過度換氣症候群 而昏倒過後
he began carrying a bag in his pocket as an emergency treatment measure.
為了對應突然復發的狀況 隨時將袋子收在口袋裡
The paper bag method
目前醫學上
is not presently endorsed from a medical perspective.
並不建議這種紙袋急救法
However, in this instance,
但是在本案件中
the accused carried it as a means of safeguarding his own life.
那個袋子是被告人為了保護 自己的生命安全而攜帶的用品
Therefore, his crime was not premeditated.
並沒有預謀犯罪的意思
PUBLIC PROSECUTORS OFFICE
（檢察廳）
REFERENCE ROOM
（閱覽室）
DNA PROFILING TEST REPORT
（DNA個人識別鑑定書）
How unusual.
真是稀客
Were you doing some research?
你是來調查的嗎？
At this rate, Hiyama's guilt will be established.
“這樣下去將會判定緋山有罪”
That's the report I've received.
我收到這樣的報告
I'm sure that is the outcome the prosecution desires.
以檢方的角度來看 那就是你們想要的結果
Those who have committed a crime
犯下罪行的人
should face appropriate judgment.
當然需要接受適當的判決
Right?
沒錯吧？
That's the ideal.
真是理想啊
The trial isn't over yet.
審判還沒有結束
Excuse me.
失陪了
The murder weapon, huh?
凶器啊？
Apparently, a police officer who happened to be patrolling the area found it.
“在附近巡邏的警官剛好找到的”
It sounds too convenient that it'd been found amid trial.
在公審進行時找到也太剛好了吧
It's suspicious.
很可疑
It was discovered on a dry riverbed two kilometers away from the crime scene
是在距離犯罪現場 兩公里遠的河灘找到的
and exposed to rain for three months.
淋了三個月的雨
Yet, they detected the victim's blood on it.
居然還能檢測出被害人的血液
Can blood linger that long?
血液可以殘留這麼久嗎？
I'm not sure.
不好說
I've heard blood on clothes can still be detected
我有聽過沾到衣服上的血
The presence of Mr. Hanegi's blood suggests it was used for the murder.
既然有檢測到羽木先生的血液 幾乎就能確定曾作為凶器使用
But even this isn't decisive evidence.
就算如此也不算是決定性的證據
True.
也是啦
The hammer belongs to Mr. Hiyama,
就算說是緋山先生的鐵鎚
but the prosecution hasn't been able to prove he used it for the murder.
檢察官也還沒證明 緋山就是用那個來殺人的
Welcome back.
回來啦
How did it go?
結果如何？
He'll get around two years, I think.
判了兩年
Thanks for getting the diagnosis on short notice.
謝謝你及時給我診斷證明書
Linking it to hyperventilation was a stretch,
雖然說是過度換氣症候群很牽強
but letting the old man die in prison would've been too pitiful.
但老爺爺這麼年邁 讓他在監獄中死去也太可憐了
Misplaced it?
弄丟了？
Mr. Hiyama misplaced his hammer before the incident,
緋山先生在事件發生前弄丟鐵鎚
and someone else used it for the crime.
之後有人將其拿來犯罪
So, it was either stolen or found by someone else.
也就是說是有人偷的或是撿到了
Something like that, I imagine.
大概是那樣沒錯
It was used without Mr. Hiyama's knowledge or consent and happened to be found.
凶器在緋山先生不知情的地方 被擅自使用，有人偶然間發現
That's all there is to it.
就只是這樣而已
No need to worry about it.
不需要特別介意
No need?
不需要特別介意？
More importantly…
比起那個…
Mr. Aoyama.
青山先生
I did some digging on Mr. Himeno.
我調查了有關姬野檢座的事情
Every year, he receives commendations from the Chief Prosecutor
他每年都受到首席檢察官表揚
for his achievements.
似乎是有持續做出成果的人
At the young age of 30,
他才年僅30歲
he was appointed the Senior Prosecutor for major incidents across a wide area.
就被提拔為廣域重要事件的 主任檢察官
He's clearly seen as promising.
看來前途一片光明
How is his background relevant?
跟檢座的經歷有什麼關係嗎？
Look at this.
請看這個
Is this a list of all the cases he's handled?
這些是他過去負責過的案件？
Yes, Mr. Akizumi looked this up.
對，是明墨律師查出來的
The cases that required DNA tests
這裡面需要鑑定DNA的案件共有…
were nine in total.
九件
All of which were handled by Professor Tadao Nakajima
負責鑑定這些的 全都跟這次的案件一樣
of Metropolitan Medical University, who also worked on this case.
是都立醫科大學的中島忠雄教授
Professor Nakajima is a leading authority in forensic medicine.
中島教授是法醫學的權威
How is his involvement relevant?
這個人怎麼了嗎？
Isn't it common for investigative authorities
搜查機關每次都委託同樣的人
to consult the same expert?
是很正常的吧？
The incident took place on January 30th of this year.
事件發生的日期是今年的1月30日
Despite ample evidence,
明明有這麼多證據
the police repeatedly requested Mr. Hiyama to come in voluntarily.
警察卻不斷刻意要求 緋山先生到警局協助調查
They also made multiple re-arrests for minor offenses like property damage,
以毀損器物罪等微小罪狀 屢次重複逮捕
and took a long time to indict him.
花了很長的一段時間才起訴
This was clearly at the instruction of the prosecutor.
明顯有負責的檢察官在背後下指示
So, they needed time until the indictment.
也就是說需要一段時間才能起訴
Was it to locate the murder weapon, which would serve as decisive evidence?
他們是在找能成為 決定性證據的凶器吧？
Or maybe…
應該有…
for another reason?
其他的理由吧？
Prosecutors are creatures that craft narratives to suit their purposes.
檢察官這種生物 會捏造對自己有利的故事
For instance…
比如說…
Consider a scenario where a capable prosecutor,
有個備受上層期待的優秀檢察官
The suspect is most certainly the culprit.
他認為“嫌疑人一定就是犯人”
The upper management believes he's 100% guilty.
上層也認為他百分之百有罪
But all they have is circumstantial evidence
然而實際上蒐集到的都是間接證據
and they still lack decisive proof.
至今尚未掌握到關鍵證據
"What do I do?"
“該怎麼辦？
"As things stand, there's a great risk
再這樣下去，被告的律師
that the defense counsel could overturn the existing evidence."
非常有可能會推翻現有的證據”
This prosecutor, precisely due to his competence,
正因為是優秀的檢查官
is attracting attention and facing immense pressure from his superiors.
才會受到矚目，需承擔上司的期待
Losing this case
如果在這個案件輸掉的話
could tarnish all the achievements he's amassed thus far.
他至今為止累積的功績就會有瑕疵
So thinking,
他如此深信
he tells himself,
於是說服自己
"That man is undoubtedly guilty."
“那傢伙一定有殺人
"For the sake of justice, I must ensure his conviction."
為了正義，要想盡辦法判他有罪
"I know."
對了
"If DNA evidence is found on the victim's body,
只要從被害人的身體 比如說指甲縫裡
such as under the nails,
檢測出DNA的話
it would be highly compelling evidence."
將會是很有效的證據”
And so,
於是呢
he directs the police to resubmit samples for DNA testing.
他向警察下達指令 要再次進行DNA鑑定
At the same time,
與此同時
he reaches out to a professor with whom he's closely connected,
聯繫有深厚情誼的教授
and requests tampering with the DNA test results.
拜託他竄改鑑定結果
That would explain the delay in making the indictment.
這麼一想，就能說明 為什麼拖了這麼久才起訴
Requesting another round of testing and inventing evidence from the results
因為委託再次鑑定 並將其結果化為證據
would take considerable time.
確實需要相當長的時間
The prosecution would never engage in tampering.
怎麼可能，檢察官不會竄改資料吧
But there is a precedent for this.
然而現實上就是有發生過
Over a decade ago,
在十多年前
there was a case where a certain system was abused.
在濫用某個制度的事件中
A Senior Prosecutor tampered with evidence data on a floppy disk.
主任檢察官就竄改了 作為證據的磁片中的資料
Even prosecutors are human.
檢察官也是人
Can you be confident it won't happen again?
你能肯定這種事情 不會再發生第二次嗎？
Even politicians, meant to embody model citizens,
即使是應該當國民楷模的政治家
have been involved in numerous egregious injustices and cover-ups.
也做出了許多 不忍直視的貪汙或隱蔽行為
Even the police have been guilty
警察也是如此
of illegal investigations, mistaken arrests,
像是非法搜查或逮捕錯犯人
There's no reason to think only the prosecution is innocent.
沒有只有檢察官 不會動任何手腳的鐵證
We should look into this.
我們該進行調查
On mere speculation?
就靠推測嗎？
Akamine.
赤峰
Every discovery and invention in the world
這世上的任何發現或發明
are built on speculation and theories.
都是以推測與假說為基礎並成立的
Excuse me.
打擾了
What happened?
怎麼了嗎？
It seems Attorney Akizumi
明墨律師他啊
has been digging into your past trial records.
好像調查了你過去進行的審判紀錄
Why was he doing that?
你覺得他要查你的理由
Any ideas?
是什麼？
No.
不曉得
Your hand.
注意你的手
You should stop that.
不要那樣做
-We're a camera club.
我們是攝影社
-Check it out.
請參考一下…
-We're a tennis club. -I can still pass as a university student.
-我們是網球社 -我還可以當學生呢
The DNA test was conducted
進行DNA鑑定的地方
in the genetic testing room at Metropolitan Medical University.
是都立醫科大學的基因檢驗室
The first thing I need you to check is the room's usage log.
首先想請你們查的 是檢驗室的使用紀錄
You can find it in the Research Management Section.
這可以去研究管理課確認
Excuse me.
不好意思
Yes?
是
I'd like to check the usage log of the genetic testing room.
我想要確認基因檢驗室 過去的使用紀錄
Your student ID, please?
請出示學生證
Right.
好
Sorry, I think I might've left it somewhere.
不好意思，我好像忘記帶過來了
But I have a participation certificate from the Genomics Conference
不過我有上個月的全國法醫學會
hosted by the National Society of Forensic Medicine the other day.
基因組學會議參加證
Along with a group photo.
還有合照
METROPOLITAN MEDICAL UNIVERSITY ASUKA SHINOMIYA
（都立醫科大學，紫之宮飛鳥）
NATIONAL SOCIETY OF FORENSIC MEDICINE GENOMICS CONFERENCE
（全國法醫學會 基因組學會議）
All right.
好吧
Just a minute.
等我一下
About that photo…
剛才那是…
We got Mr. Aoyama to prepare it.
我們請青山先生準備的
It's a composite photo.
照片也是合成的
We didn't fabricate a student ID, so we're just skirting the law.
反正又不是偽造學生證 勉強不會有問題吧
Don't let it show that you're disturbed.
不要面露不安的表情
I was terrified thinking what would happen if they found out you took a photo.
你還拍了照片 害我很擔心是否會敗露
The online career fair,
線上就職說明會
when's the deadline to apply for it?
申請截止日是什麼時候？
Well…
這個嘛
As stated in the report, on February 1st,
如同筆錄所述，在2月1日
a DNA test was carried out right after the legally-ordered autopsy.
在執行司法解剖後 馬上進行了DNA檢驗
Mr. Aoyama, I've just sent it to you.
青山先生，我剛剛傳過去了
Hold on.
等一下…
I see.
原來如此
It seems the test was indeed conducted on February 1st.
看來在2月1日進行檢驗是真的
In that case,
這樣的話
the typical turnaround for test results is about a week.
檢驗結果大概會在一週後寄送
So, the prosecution would likely receive them
也就是說，檢察官確認結果的時間
around February 7th or 8th.
會落在2月7號或8號
But Mr. Hiyama's DNA wasn't identified in this test.
但在那項檢驗 並沒有驗出緋山先生的DNA
That's our assumption, right?
可以這麼想吧？
Yes.
是的
This put pressure on the prosecution,
覺得不妙，陷入焦急的檢察官
prompting them to ask Professor Nakajima for another test
應該有請中島教授再次進行鑑定
to ensure that Mr. Hiyama's DNA would appear.
請他將緋山先生的DNA沾上去
If they intended to tamper with the results,
假設真是如此
why bother with another test at all?
為什麼竄改資料會需要再次鑑定呢？
DNA test reports are protected with anti-copying watermarks,
DNA鑑定書上有防止複製的浮水印
making it difficult to directly alter them.
很難直接修改
If the original data is tampered with,
所以即使硬是修改原本的資料
they say specialists can easily detect artificial alterations.
專家也能馬上看出人為竄改的痕跡
But how did they acquire Mr. Hiyama's DNA?
但要怎麼準備緋山先生的DNA？
If the prosecution conducted a DNA test,
檢察官說“做了DNA鑑定”
it implies they already had Mr. Hiyama provide them with a DNA sample.
就代表他們已經 從緋山先生身上取得了DNA
I see.
我懂了
After all, they're comparing the skin found under the victim's nails
檢方當時在確認被害人 指甲縫間的皮膚上的DNA
with the voluntarily provided DNA sample from Mr. Hiyama.
與從緋山先生身上 自願提供的DNA是否一致
In other words, the prosecution possesses Mr. Hiyama's DNA,
也就是說以正當理由 取得的緋山先生的DNA
which they obtained for a legitimate purpose.
在檢方手上對吧？
I see.
是這樣啊
They likely took Mr. Hiyama's DNA,
他們將緋山先生的DNA
mixed it with the sample supposedly collected from under the victim's nails,
以及從被害人指甲縫間取得的樣本
and had Professor Nakajima conduct another test.
兩者混合在一起 讓中島教授再次進行鑑定
This was carried out in utmost secrecy, of course.
這一切當然都是祕密進行的
If another test was conducted
如果進行再次鑑定
and the data was submitted within the detention period…
要在拘留期間內再次傳送檔案的話…
The second test would have occurred
進行二次鑑定的時間就會是
sometime between…
2月9號
February 9th and 15th.
到15號之間
If the second test occurred sometime between February 9th and 15th…
假設是在2月9號到15號之間 進行再次鑑定
Professor Nakajima lectures at another university
中島教授在其他學校
on Tuesdays and Wednesdays, and those weren't canceled.
只有週二與週三有課，並沒有停課
So, he could've only come to the Medical University
也就是說他能來醫科大的日子
on Monday, Thursday, and Friday.
就是週一、週四、週五
And the only day the testing room was available on one of these three days…
週一、週四、週五中 檢驗室有開的日子是…
was the 15th.
15號
There's an odd gap here.
這些空白欄位好不自然
This is probably when the second test was conducted.
應該就是在這段時間再次鑑定
That would be it.
沒錯
This is the research building.
這就是研究大樓
No security cameras here.
似乎沒有監視器
GENETIC TESTING ROOM
（基因檢驗室）
It won't open unless we know the passcode.
不知道密碼就無法打開
Oh my, hello!
哎呀，大家好！
Are you here for some tests?
現在要進行檢驗嗎？
Well, we thought we'd do some prep.
這個嘛，想說來做一下準備
Being a student is tough, huh?
學生真是辛苦啊
Good luck and work hard for Japan.
要加油喔，這都是為了日本
-Thank you. -No problem.
-謝謝你 -不客氣
We'll do our best.
我們會加油的
That gave me a fright.
嚇死人了
The look on your face when that lady appeared was priceless.
話說那位大嬸出來時 紫之宮小姐的表情好誇張喔
I never knew you could make that expression, Shinomiya.
小紫也會露出那種表情啊
Oh my!
哎呀！
Good day.
辛苦了
Um…
話說回來
Are tests typically conducted by the professor alone?
檢驗一般來說是 由教授獨自進行的嗎？
-Huh? -I mean…
-什麼？ -我的意思是…
There's preparation to do,
畢竟還需要做準備
and it must be a lot of work for just one person.
只由一個人做應該滿辛苦的
And to do it without anyone noticing sounds quite tricky.
而且進行時還要不被任何人發現 還滿困難的不是嗎？
I'll ask some students in the forensic medicine classroom.
我去問一下法醫學教室的學生
What? Professor Nakajima's assistant?
什麼？中島教授的助手？
Exactly!
對…
I'm studying DNA testing at my graduate school,
我在研究所鑽研DNA鑑定
and I was hoping Professor Nakajima might be recruiting assistants.
所以想知道中島教授 有沒有在招募助手之類的
Tough luck. He always works with the same person.
不可能啦，他都有固定的幫手
What, really? Who?
什麼？真的嗎？是誰啊？
What's the name again? The dull-looking one.
叫什麼來著？就是那個不起眼的人
Mito, the assistant professor.
水卜助教
A Nakajima research graduate aspiring to become a professor.
他是中島研的畢業生 目標似乎是當上教授
Interesting.
是這樣啊
By the way, about this Mito person…
話說那位水卜…
I never knew she could smile like that.
原來她也能夠露出那種笑容啊
-Here you go. -Let me see…
給你
Isn't that Mito?
是這位吧？
I see.
原來如此
Mito is a nickname for Kentaro Miura.
他全名叫水卜健太朗 所以才有這種暱稱啊
Let's see what he teaches.
他負責的課程是
"Introduction to Forensic Medicine Part One."
“法醫學概論一”
Just one class, huh?
只有這門課啊？
Being an assistant professor is pretty tough, huh?
當助教在社會上不好混吧
You need to write a ton of papers and reach full professorship
聽說不努力寫論文成為教授的話
-The class should be ending soon, right? -Yes.
剛好下課時間到了
I'll go talk to him.
我去打聽一下
-I'll join you. -No need.
-我也一起去 -不用了
Ms. Shinomiya is so cool.
紫之宮小姐真是帥氣
-I see. -Thank you.
謝謝招待
If you want to win her, you should be ready.
如果你想追她的話最好要做覺悟喔
Her dad's a detective.
小紫的爸爸可是刑警
-A detective? -Yeah.
刑警？
So she's the daughter of a detective.
所以她是刑警的女兒啊
I see.
是喔
It's not like that.
我不是那個意思
Death Education, right?
《死亡教育》是嗎？
That's right.
是的
I need to write a report
我詢問中島教授
on biological death and social death in forensic medicine.
有關“法醫學中的生物性死亡 與社會性死亡”
When I asked Professor Nakajima for advice,
這個報告作業的問題
he mentioned that the book Death Education would be helpful.
他告訴我可以 參考《死亡教育》這本書
And he said I could borrow it from his bookshelf.
還說可以直接從教授的書櫃拿走
I see.
是這樣啊
Excuse me.
打擾了
Death Education should be around here.
《死亡教育》我記得是在這裡
Here you go.
來，就是這本
Thank you so much.
謝謝你
There's another book.
還有一本書
Modern Forensic Medicine: Second Revised Edition.
《現代法醫學，改訂第二版》
Excuse me.
不好意思
Found it.
那麼…
Here.
這本書也給你
-Take this too. -Thank you.
-也拿去吧 -謝謝
I hope your report goes well.
祝你能寫出一份好報告
Me too.
我會努力
Wait.
請等一下
Anything else?
還有什麼事？
I'm actually researching for a paper on the latest DNA testing methods.
其實我為了寫有關 最新DNA鑑定的論文正在進行調查
And I want some real DNA test data.
無論如何都想要DNA鑑定的真實資料
Is it possible for me to observe an actual test?
請問之後可以讓我實際參與檢驗嗎？
I've heard that you assist Professor Nakajima during tests.
我聽說水卜老師 在擔任中島教授的檢驗助手
I regret to say this,
很抱歉
but that's pretty tricky, especially since it's related to criminal cases.
因為攸關刑事案件 不太方便讓你實際參與
Of course.
我想也是
You're right.
真不好意思
What about the samples you used for testing
那鑑定時的樣本
or detailed records of tests that I could examine?
或是檢驗的詳細紀錄等 都沒留下來吧？
We return the samples,
樣本我們都會還回去
and the test results are all documented in the test report.
檢驗結果都記錄在鑑定書裡了
But we always print out the data and save it as a file.
不過數據都會印出來 保存在資料夾中
And the DNA sequencer itself should retain the raw data.
DNA序列分析儀裡面 應該也留有原始檔
The data file of the DNA test?
DNA檢驗的資料夾？
That's right.
對
Anyway,
話說回來
you managed to win over Mr. Miura quite cleverly, didn't you?
真虧你能獲得水卜教授的信任
Mr. Akizumi sent me this.
因為明墨律師有傳這訊息給我
When I asked Mr. Miura to lend me these books, he believed I was a student.
跟他說我要借這本書 他就相信我是學生了
Mr. Akizumi is as impressive as ever.
真不愧是他啊
You look like a university student.
而且你看起來很像大學生嘛
I'm so embarrassed.
真是害羞
You must've been working late.
忙到這麼晚啊，真是辛苦了
Early this year,
今年年初
there was a homicide at a factory called Hanegi Seiko in Ota Ward.
位於大田區的 羽木精工工廠發生了殺人事件
You're familiar with it, right?
你知道這件事吧？
I'm Akizumi, the defense counsel for the case.
我是負責那起案件的律師，敝姓明墨
What do you want?
你找我做什麼？
I've been looking into the DNA test conducted by Professor Nakajima.
我針對中島教授的DNA鑑定 做了一些調查
I wasn't involved in that at all.
跟我沒有任何關係
I want to check the detailed records of the DNA test on Mr. Hanegi
我想確認於2月1日進行的
conducted on February 1st.
羽木先生的DNA詳細紀錄
May I ask for your cooperation?
可以請你協助嗎？
They've been submitted to the prosecution.
那些資料已全數提交給檢察官了
So you are involved, after all.
你果然有幫忙嘛
No, I'm not.
我沒有
It was a logical assumption.
我只是照常理假設而已
Excuse me.
我可以走了吧？
One last question.
最後還有一個問題
What is it?
什麼啊？
Where were you from 1 to 6 p.m. on February 15th?
2月15日的下午一點到六點間 你人在哪裡？
I'm in a rush. Excuse me.
我在趕時間，先走了
Are you sure Mr. Miura will show up?
水卜助教真的會來嗎？
His friends were mentioning
他對於擔任中島教授的助教這件事
that he's quite unhappy about being an assistant to Professor Nakajima.
目前似乎相當不滿 他的朋友們都異口同聲地這麼說
When did he investigate that?
是何時調查的啊？
He seemed frightened throughout.
他看起來始終都很害怕
When people are nervous or under extreme stress,
人類一感到緊張或極大的壓力
they sometimes fidget with what they're wearing.
就會去摸戴在身上的東西
He's probably been carrying a lot of anxiety and fear.
我想他是一直以來都抱持著 不安與恐懼的情緒生活吧
You met Mr. Miura?
你去見水卜助教了？
I unsettled him a bit last night.
昨晚我有稍微去刺激他一下
But it's still just speculation.
但都還只是臆測而已吧
If he realizes he's suspected of illegal activity,
一旦得知自己被懷疑參與造假行為
it should make him feel uneasy.
他就會開始坐立難安
Then, he will become concerned about the raw data of the test results
如此一來，他肯定會開始 在意檢驗結果的原始檔還在的事
and try to take it outside.
並試圖將其移到外面
If he won't let us into the testing room,
既然不讓我們進去檢驗室
we'll need to get him to bring it to us.
就只能請他帶來給我們
The testing room is available only now for today.
今天只有這段時間檢驗室沒有人
Well then,
好
let us wait.
我們就等等看吧
And so, it falls on me again.
結果又是叫我做
He's here.
他來了
I guess I can't tell the passcode.
果然看不出密碼是什麼
DNA TEST RESULTS
（DNA鑑定結果）
Hello.
你好
I'm Akamine from the Akizumi Law Office.
我是明墨法律事務所的赤峰
Mr. Miura,
水卜老師
no test was scheduled for today.
今天應該沒有安排檢驗
Why are you here?
但你為什麼會來？
Were you looking for something?
你是來找某樣東西的吧？
What are you talking about?
我不明白你在說什麼
Please show me the contents of your bag.
若是如此，請讓我看包包裡面裝什麼
Hey!
站住！
Wait a minute!
等一下
It's not here.
沒找到
I just came back for my stuff.
我只是來拿忘記拿的東西而已
How dare you!
你是在幹嘛？
You're from a law office, right?
你是律師吧？
I'll report this to my superiors.
我會向上層報告這件事
Excuse me.
再見
I should've gone instead.
應該要由我去
But he already knows your face, Ms. Shinomiya.
不過他已經知道你長什麼樣子了
Well, it's too late now.
算了，這也沒辦法
Mr. Akizumi, did you suspect this might happen?
明墨律師，你一開始 就預料到會變成這樣了吧？
I sincerely apologize.
真的很抱歉
Mr. Akizumi,
明墨律師
this is unacceptable behavior from an attorney.
身為律師，做這種事太離譜了
My apologies.
不好意思
I had no idea he'd commit such a blunder.
我沒想到他會這麼做
He's young, yes, but he definitely crossed a line.
雖說他還年輕，但做法太過分是事實
I'll give him a stern reprimand.
我會確實教導他的
If you'll excuse us.
先告辭了
Do you think a simple apology will let you off the hook?
你以為道歉就沒事了嗎？
Is there something else?
還有什麼事嗎？
What this man did is an insult to me.
這男人所做的事是在侮辱我
Excuse me?
在胡說什麼？
You're quite brazen yourself.
你的態度也很囂張嘛
Your actions have greatly diminished trust and order among attorneys.
你們所做的事情
Wouldn't you agree?
我說的沒錯吧？
Quite.
沒錯
I'll be bringing this matter to the disciplinary committee.
我會向懲戒委員會提出申訴
I've known Attorney Kawana, the chairperson, for quite some time now.
我跟身為委員長的 川名律師可是老朋友呢
-If I speak-- -I'm impressed, Professor Nakajima.
-只要我提出… -真不愧是中島教授
You wield quite the authority.
說話真是有分量啊
And it's not just him.
不光是他
I'll also be holding you responsible as his supervisor.
我也會請他們追究 身為上司的你該負的監督責任
By all means.
請便
Now, if you'll excuse us.
那我們就此告辭
Let's go.
走吧
I almost forgot.
對了
Do send my regards.
能請你幫忙打聲招呼嗎？
To Prosecutor Himeno.
跟姬野檢座說一聲
That wasn't fair, Mr. Akizumi.
你太狡猾了，明墨律師
You just tried to pin all the blame on me.
你剛剛居然想把責任都推到我身上
Did I?
有嗎？
What's our next move?
接下來該怎麼做？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
The raw data evidence has likely been destroyed.
原始檔這項證據可能被消除了
If so, we won't be able to uncover the tampering of the test results anymore.
這樣不就無從得知 檢查結果有被竄改過了嗎？
At this rate, we'll really face disciplinary action.
要是無所作為 我們真的會受到懲戒處分
Don't worry.
沒事的
We simply have to expose them before the trial.
只要在審判前揭發造假行為 一切都能圓滿解決
Still…
可是…
Excuse me, I have a place to stop by.
失陪了，我要順便去某個地方
Come on.
什麼？
Don't worry about it.
別擔心啦
You still have a long life ahead of you.
人生還有很長一段路要走
I don't know…
我不確定耶…
Listen, we can't have you feeling down like this.
聽好了，你這麼低落我也很困擾
Here. The old lady confessed to the theft.
你看這個，奶奶承認自己順手牽羊了
Also, the food and drinks you had at the racetrack won't count as expenses.
還有這個，在賽馬場 吃飯的錢是沒辦法報帳的
And guess what? There's more.
還有喔，可不只有這些
She's a taskmaster.
有惡魔，你真的是魔鬼
If an attorney throws in the towel,
如果律師放棄的話
who's the client supposed to turn to?
委託人該依靠誰才好呢？
Mr. Akizumi hasn't given up yet.
明墨律師還沒有放棄喔
DRY CLEANER
（洗衣店）
Did you come here alone?
你是一個人來嗎？
The DNA found under the victim's nails might have been tampered with.
從被害人的指甲驗到的 DNA檢驗結果可能有被造假
Tampered with?
造假？
During the investigation by the prosecution,
你在檢方訊問時
did you consent to giving a DNA sample?
有同意採取DNA對吧？
Basically,
也就是說
the prosecution can do as they want with your DNA.
檢方能用任何方法使用你的DNA
If they mixed it in
如果你的DNA
with the sample collected from under the victim's nails…
被混進從被害人的指甲 採取的樣本中…
That can't be…
怎麼可能
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm here because I was encouraged not to give up.
我被勸誡“不要放棄” 所以才來到這裡
But
可是呢
we couldn't get evidence of the tampering.
我們已經無法取得證明有造假的證據
Mr. Akizumi will do something, won't he?
明墨律師會想辦法幫我吧？
Mr. Hiyama,
緋山先生
may I ask you a question?
我可以問你一個問題嗎？
You didn't…
你真的…
kill Mr. Hanegi, right?
沒有殺掉羽木先生對吧？
No.
沒有
I…
我…
came to this law office because I admired Mr. Akizumi.
是因為仰慕明墨律師 才進入這間事務所
Six months ago, he handled a false accusation case.
契機是半年前發生的冤案事件
Seeing him save an innocent person,
看到拯救無辜之人的他後
I was inspired to be like him.
我也希望自己能變成那種人
I wanted to help people too.
一心想要拯救別人
This case is the same, isn't it?
我這次也可以這麼認為吧？
We're doing all this
為了證明你的清白
to prove your innocence, right?
我們正在努力奔走，沒錯吧？
I…
我…
Are you two finished?
你們講完了嗎？
Mr. Akizumi.
明墨律師
Mr. Hiyama,
緋山先生
don't worry.
你不需要擔心
There's no reason for you to be convicted.
你沒有被判有罪的理由
Akamine,
赤峰
I'll show you how to win a trial.
我會讓你見識到所謂的勝訴方法
Regarding the murder weapon, yes, it has been found.
關於凶器，只能這麼說
But there's no evidence linking the accused to its use in the murder.
雖然有找到實體，但還沒有找到證據
That is all I can say.
證明被告人用此凶器殺了人
It doesn't matter.
無所謂
It's up to the lay judges to decide.
反正判斷的是陪審團的各位
Later today,
另外今天呢
I will be examining the witness Professor Nakajima,
有安排針對負責DNA鑑定的
who conducted the DNA tests.
中島教授的證人訊問
I plan to ask a few questions during that session.
到時候我會問他一些問題
The DNA from the skin flake discovered under the victim's nails
附著在被害人指甲上的 皮膚的DNA型態
is a complete match to the DNA of the accused.
跟被告人的DNA型態完全一致
suggests there was a tussle between the two.
可以推測出兩者曾扭打在一起
Thank you.
謝謝你
That is all from me.
檢方沒有要補充的了
Defense counsel, you may begin your cross-examination.
那麼請辯護人進行反詰問
Professor,
教授
you've been involved in many investigations
你以法醫學權威之姿
concerning causes of death as an authority in forensic medicine.
參與多起由檢方主導的死因調查案件
Is it accurate to say that genetic testing was conducted exclusively
其中的基因檢驗全都是 在醫學院的基因檢驗室進行的
That is correct.
沒有
In this room that adheres to strict hygiene and security protocols?
在衛生以及安全管理 都很萬全的檢驗室裡？
As I said, that is correct.
所以我說了，並沒有錯
There would be no way for anyone outside
也就是說你在裡面做什麼
to know the specifics of what happens inside, correct?
外面的人都完全無法知道，對吧？
Listen.
我跟你說
Test results indicate the date and are accompanied by the test data.
檢驗結果中有附上日期跟檢驗資料
His DNA was found.
有驗到他的DNA
That has been established.
那一點已經被證實了
Now, now, let's not get impatient.
別激動，不要這麼焦急
We have plenty of time.
我們有很多時間
The DNA test of the victim was conducted on February 1st,
進行被害人DNA檢驗的日期
as stated in the test report. Is that correct?
如同鑑定書記載 是2月1日沒有錯吧？
That's correct.
沒錯
Was it just that once?
只有那麼一次吧？
What are you getting at?
你從剛剛開始到底想說什麼？
Defense counsel, clarify the intent behind your questions.
請辯護人具體講明問題的目的
Apologies.
抱歉
I will be straightforward.
那就讓我講得更明確一點吧
Professor, did you conduct DNA testing
教授，這次的DNA檢驗
not just once, but twice?
你不只是做一次 還做了第二次對吧？
To refresh his memory,
為了讓你想起來
I'd like to present evidence number 42 as requested by the defense counsel.
容我出示辯護人請求證據第42號證據
Please examine this document.
請看這份資料
It's a record of DNA tests conducted in the testing room
這是2月9日到15日的這一週
during the week of February 9th to the 15th.
在檢驗室中進行的DNA鑑定一覽表
-It's just your standard record. -It is.
-就只是一般的紀錄啊 -對
There is nothing unusual about it.
這份紀錄中沒有奇怪的地方
However, take note of this.
但是請看這邊
On February 15th, between 1 and 6 p.m.,
2月15日下午一點到下午六點的部分
there's a blank in the usage log.
是沒有使用紀錄的空白欄位
A second round of testing may have occurred during this time.
在這段期間 你可能進行了第二次檢驗
Professor Nakajima, any comments regarding this?
中島教授，有什麼話想說嗎？
What do you expect me to say?
就算你問我也沒用啊
I'm not sure what this is all about.
我又搞不懂你在說什麼
Is that so?
是嗎？
I, Shinomiya, of the defense counsel,
針對詢問內容，辯護人紫之宮
would like to clarify the premise for this questioning.
來為各位整理前提狀況
As previously mentioned,
如同方才所述
the genetic testing room maintains strict hygiene protocols.
DNA檢驗室有進行嚴密的衛生管理
Individuals entering the room are required to wear designated white coats.
入內時需穿著專用的白色作業服
And once used, these coats are placed in a cart for weekly cleaning.
穿過的作業服會丟進推車裡 以便每週拿去送洗一次
Professor, is my information correct so far?
教授，至此為止我說的都沒錯吧？
It is.
對
In order to refresh his memory,
那為了讓你的記憶更加鮮明
I will present evidence number 43 as requested by the defense counsel.
容我出示辯護人請求證據 第43號證據的資料
Take a look at this document.
請看這份資料
The room was used 18 times by a total of 33 individuals.
總計使用18次，共有33人使用
Therefore, there should be 33 coats collected from the cart.
也就是說
However, for some reason, 35 coats were collected.
然而不知道為什麼卻收回了35件
COLLECTION RECORD
（收回紀錄表）
I directly confirmed this information with the cleaning dealer responsible.
這是我親自去跟負責 收回作業服的洗衣業者確認的
Wait a minute.
給我等一下
Are you suggesting I conducted another test based solely on that?
你光憑那一點就認定我有再次鑑定？
There's no evidence we used those two coats for another test.
沒有證據證明 這兩件衣服是我們穿的啊
Your Honor, are you going to allow this?
庭上，你能容許這種論述嗎？
By the way,
順帶一提
what were you doing between 1 and 6 p.m. on February 15th?
教授在2月15日的 下午一點到下午六點在做什麼呢？
During that time on Thursday,
我想想，星期四的那時候
I had a meeting with Assistant Professor Miura.
我在跟水卜助教開會
Is that so?
這樣啊？
That came out quite smoothly, almost as if you had rehearsed it.
感覺你事先就準備這樣回答 講得很順耶
Did you perhaps anticipate this question?
你該不會知道會被這樣問吧？
I have meetings with him at this time every Thursday.
我們在週四那段時間一定都會開會
You'll see if you ask Miura yourself.
你去問水卜，馬上就能確認了
Well, I did.
你說得對
I did ask him.
我就是有問過
Now, I would like to request new evidence.
我在此申請新的證據
Wait a minute!
等一下！
This hasn't been disclosed to the prosecution in advance.
該不會又是沒有事先 開示給檢方的證據吧？
This cannot be acknowledged!
不能同意採納！
The prosecutor is right.
如同檢察官所說
Introducing new evidence at this stage--
你在這時提出新證據…
This is crucial evidence
這份證據
that will completely overturn Professor Nakajima's test results.
會徹底推翻教授的鑑定結果 可說是極為重要
I apologize for the delayed request as it was obtained at the last minute.
我是在快開庭前拿到的 所以來不及申請，真的很抱歉
However, disregarding this evidence would not only hinder the discovery of truth,
但如果湮滅這項證據
In order to prevent a false accusation, I urge you to allow this.
為了防止冤案發生，希望庭上能准許
That's sophistry!
根本是狡辯！
Your Honor,
庭上
I ask you not to be misled by an attorney with no respect for the rules.
不要被辯護人無視規定的做法迷惑了
Please render a fair judgment.
請下達公正的判斷
Prosecutor,
檢察官
do you still have more to say?
你還有什麼要說的嗎？
Still more to say?
還有什麼要說的？
Preventing a false accusation is the primary objective of a trial.
防止冤案是審判最重要的目的
Your responsibility is to examine the evidence and offer your opinion on it.
請檢方先確認證據後再提出意見
Is that understood?
可以吧？
Now, I will play the footage of evidence number 48,
那麼請容我播放
Please watch the video.
請看
Professor Nakajima asked you to provide an alibi for him
中島教授請你說出2月15日當天
by claiming that you were having a meeting with him on February 15th.
你們一起開了根本不存在的會議 麻煩你準備不在場證明
Is this correct?
那是真的嗎？
Mr. Miura?
水卜先生
Yes.
對
That's correct.
你說的沒錯
Was this request made
那是為了跟教授在極度機密的狀態下
in order to conduct another DNA test with the professor in secret?
再次鑑定DNA嗎？
That's right.
是的
Considering your position,
你在立場上
you could not disobey the professor.
無法違抗教授的命令
That's right.
是的
Why did you choose to come forward with the truth?
為什麼這次會老實回答呢？
As someone involved in forensic medicine,
身為從事法醫學工作的人
I couldn't remain silent.
我無法坐視不管
Thank you for your courageous act of whistle-blowing.
謝謝你鼓起勇氣告發
Professor,
教授
this is Mr. Miura's testimony that you wanted.
這就是你想聽的水卜先生的證詞
Stop messing around!
別開玩笑了！
You coerced him into providing false testimony!
他是被你強迫說出假的證詞！
Bring him here!
叫本人過來！
He was intimidated by your high-handed manner,
他就是害怕你那種高壓的態度
which is why he provided a video testimony.
才用錄影的方式提出證詞
As a precaution,
為了以防萬一
I have also prepared a written statement signed by Mr. Miura himself.
我準備了水卜先生本人署名的告發文
I will later request this as evidence for the same reasons
這份文件跟剛才的影片 稍後會以同樣的理由
as the footage just now.
去請求證據
Along with a handwriting analysis certificate.
同時也會提出筆跡鑑定書
Order.
肅靜
By the way,
另外呢
the raw data of the test results
鑑定結果的原始檔
has already been suppressed by Professor Nakajima.
已經由中島教授之手被處理掉
However, evidence of tampering remains
但是竄改的證據
as it has been personally duplicated and stored by Mr. Miura.
水卜助教本人 有私自複製並保存，所以還在
As the defense counsel, I urge Your Honor to verify this firsthand ex-officio.
身為辯護人
Wouldn't you agree, Professor Nakajima?
我說的都沒錯吧？中島教授
As you can all discern by now,
如同大家所了解的
the accused's DNA was never present under the victim's nails to begin with.
原本被害人的指甲 並沒有沾到被告人的DNA
However, through deliberate manipulation,
然而你卻在第二次檢驗時
you made the accused's DNA appear in a second round of testing.
故意沾上被告人的DNA
I imagine you only did as you were instructed.
應該說是被請求那麼做
Did you receive financial compensation from the prosecution for this?
你是不是有收到檢方給的錢呢？
You were seeking instruction on what to do just now.
你剛剛是不知道怎麼應對 想要求救對吧？
N-No!
不是！
Prosecutor,
檢察官
you failed to gather sufficient evidence to indict the accused.
沒能湊齊足以起訴被告人的證據的你
And so you resorted to such underhanded tactics.
用了這種骯髒手段
That is baseless speculation!
這是你在擅自臆測
I might as well conjecture
說到臆測，我也想順便請問一下
that you've employed similar methods in the past.
你之前是不是也用過同樣的手法呢？
After all, this method can be used as many times as you wish.
畢竟只要用同樣的方法 執行好幾次都沒問題
In Japan's criminal case trials, the conviction rate stands at 99.9%,
日本的刑事案件審判 判定有罪的機率為99.9%
a fact often depicted in dramas.
這一點在連續劇中也有提到過
In other words, when a prosecutor brings charges against someone,
也就是說，只要檢察官起訴
their conviction is almost guaranteed.
就能確定有罪
However, the weight of this statistic does not fall most
最能從此數字感受到沉重壓力的人
on us attorneys.
並非我們律師
But on the prosecutors.
而是檢方
"Japan's investigative agencies won't make a wrongful arrest."
“日本的搜查機關很優秀 所以不可能逮捕錯人”
People believe in their competency and the trust cannot be destroyed.
不能背叛如此確信的國民們 抱持的期待
Prosecutors feel compelled to secure convictions.
起訴後就一定要讓判決結果是有罪
They are burdened by obligations that don't exist.
檢方有義務去遵守這項無形規定
This pressure took a toll on this man,
就是那股沉重的壓力把他逼到絕境
leading to his unlawful actions.
使他進行這次的竄改行為
Don't we all have such experiences?
各位是否也有經歷過？
Anyone belonging to an organization must know what it's like to bend yourself
只要是隸屬於組織的任何人
to conform to mindsets established by the whole.
最終只能委屈自己的經驗
You suppress your own feelings for your livelihoods and families.
為了生活、為了家人 只能壓抑自己的感情
It is difficult to oppose rules that are already in place.
對於既定規範，很難開口反對
Mr. Hiyama didn't speak out against power harassment,
不論是緋山先生 無法為遭受職權騷擾的事情發聲
and Mr. Ogata kept concealing his hearing impairment.
還是尾形先生一直 隱瞞自己耳朵生病的事
They did so to survive. It couldn't be helped.
一切都是為了生存而做的無奈之舉
Unfortunately, that is the reality of Japan's current society.
很遺憾，現在的日本依然是這種社會
However, we and all individuals involved in the administration of justice,
不過負責執行司法的人，包括我們
must never forget for a moment that they hold the power
一秒都不能忘記自己所處的立場
to determine someone's fate.
會左右他人的一生
A distorted perspective can unjustly rob the life of an innocent person
扭曲的想法會奪走希望平穩生活的
who simply seeks a quiet life.
無辜之人的人生
We must never let that happen!
絕對不能容許那種事發生！
Your Honor,
庭上
the same holds true for you.
我也能對你們說同樣的話
You must not become consumed with simply completing trials,
如果你們只想著拚命將多個案件結案
and neglect to question the evidence presented by the prosecution
絲毫不懷疑檢方提出的證據
before rendering your judgments.
就下達判決
Otherwise, you won't be fulfilling your duties.
那也等於完全沒有盡到應有的義務
This court is where people judge others,
我衷心希望這個法庭
and it should be a place where fair judgments prevail.
在由某人去制裁另一人時
That is my earnest wish.
可以進行公正的審判
Fair judgments.
進行公正的審判
32-YEAR-OLD MAN CONVICTED IN INJURY CASE IN SHIBUYA WARD
（32歲男性被判有罪 澀谷區路邊傷害事件）
MR. MATSUNAGA IS INNOCENT
（松永先生並沒有犯罪！）
REAL CULPRIT IS SHOICHIRO!!
（真正的犯人是正一郎！）
Thank you all for today.
在場的各位，今天真是辛苦了
The court is now adjourned.
就此退庭
Mr. Akizumi,
明墨律師，你是怎麼 讓水卜先生站在我們這邊的？
Didn't I tell you?
我說過了吧？
I wasn't involved in that at all.
此事跟我沒有關係
We will investigate the professor's unlawful testing practices in court.
我們將會在法院追究教授的捏造行為
We're even considering exposing this to the media.
也考慮向媒體爆料
If that happens,
那樣的話
you'll also be accused as an accomplice.
他們也會追究身為幫手的你的罪行
I read the latest paper on DNA profiling employing haplotype analysis.
“使用單倍型分析技術的 DNA型個人識別”的最新論文
It was submitted under Professor Nakajima's name,
這份論文是以中島教授的名義登錄的
but you're the actual author, aren't you?
但其實是你寫的對吧？
How do you know?
為什麼你會知道？
Writing habits are evident in text, and not just in handwriting.
文章都會有所謂的書寫習慣 不光是筆跡
A writer's habits appear in typed content and even in English texts.
用電腦打出來的文字或英文 都會顯現出個人的習慣
When using negative sentences, Professor Nakajima uses words
中島教授他在寫否定型時
like "can't" and "didn't" and abbreviates them.
都會寫“can't”或是“didn't”
On the other hand…
與之相反，你的話呢
you tend to write "can not."
會寫成“can not”
You write "not" individually to emphasize a strong negative.
藉由分開寫出“not” 強調否定的意思
As if to say
彷彿是在說
that this wasn't written by Professor Nakajima.
“這份論文並不是中島教授寫的”
This was written by you.
這份論文是你寫的
From this paper as well,
從此論文也能看出來
I can see well that you're highly competent.
你真的是非常優秀的人才
However,
然而…
the professor will never acknowledge your talents.
教授絕對不會認同你對吧？
He prefers to keep someone as skilled as you under his control
因為他想讓頂尖的你在他底下
and continue to take advantage of you.
好繼續利用你為他做事
It's often superiors like him who claim, "I'm acting in your best interest."
那種上司應該特別愛說 “我這麼做是在為你著想”之類的
What will you do?
你要怎麼做？
Will you continue to be the professor's accomplice?
要變成教授的共犯嗎？
If that is your decision,
如果那是你的決定
I will pursue you both…
我會對你也窮追不捨
to the ends of the earth.
直到你們倆走投無路
Does that mean…
也就是說
you anticipated his decision to expose the professor?
明墨律師預料到他會告發？
He simply chose his own future.
他只是自己選擇了未來
Mr. Akizumi, about this trial…
明墨律師，有關這場審判…
Please share your comments.
請你說明一下
The prosecutor may have fabricated evidence
檢方有可能跟法醫學者
in collaboration with a forensic scientist.
聯手捏造證據
This is a blatant affront to the judicial system of our nation.
只能說這種行為 褻瀆了國家的司法制度
It's something that should never happen.
不能容許的事情發生了
The prosecution will probably claim that Mr. Himeno acted alone
檢方或許會將此視作 是姬野檢座的個人行為
and firmly deny any involvement.
貫徹毫不知情的態度
But I wonder if others were truly unaware of these actions.
不過究竟是不是真的沒有人知情呢？
Excuse me.
恕我失陪
-Mr. Akizumi!
-明墨律師！
I will now deliver the verdict.
那麼下達判決結果
The decision.
主文
The accused…
被告人
is found innocent.
無罪
Next, I will explain the reasoning behind this verdict.
接下來陳述判決理由
I ask the accused to listen to this while seated.
請被告人坐下來聽
The reasoning behind this verdict.
判決理由
This incident took place on January 30th, 2024, around 9:40 p.m.,
本案件為令和6年 1月30日晚上9點40分左右
at 7-6-1 Omori-kita, Ota Ward, Tokyo,
發生在東京都大田區 大森北7丁目6番地1號
at the residence of Asao Hanegi.
關於羽木朝雄
The accused worked at Hanegi Seiko Corporation,
被告人所任職的 羽木精工股份有限公司代表董事
The accused allegedly struck him from behind with the intent to murder…
遭人懷著殺意重擊頭部…
Stop here!
到此為止！
-Stop here! -Mr. Hiyama!
-別再前進！ -緋山先生！
You're on your own from here.
之後就要靠你自己了
Mr. Hiyama!
緋山先生！
Mr. Akizumi,
明墨先生
as an attorney, how do you see this verdict?
身為辯護人 你對這判決有什麼想法？
It was indeed a challenging case.
是非常棘手的案件
But I believe the court has reached an appropriate judgment.
但是我認為法院下了適切的判斷
Later investigations uncovered
在之後的調查發現姬野檢座
a monetary transaction between Prosecutor Himeno
與都立醫科大學的中島教授
and Professor Nakajima of Metropolitan Medical University.
有金錢往來
Mr. Yashiro, was Professor Nakajima
八代先生，也就是說中島教授
instructed by Prosecutor Himeno to alter the test report?
被姬野檢座命令竄改鑑定書是嗎？
This is quite unprecedented.
真是史無前例啊
Fabricating evidence in a trial and…
捏造審判的證據…
Things are really blowing up.
事情鬧得好大啊
The prosecution will probably appeal the verdict, though.
但檢方應該會提出控訴吧
They'll want to convict Mr. Hiyama by any means necessary.
他們應該會竭盡所能地 讓緋山先生被判有罪
This case is only the beginning.
“這事件還只是序幕”
Did I sound like him?
很像他吧？
I've always wanted to try.
我只是想說說看
That was pretty good.
-還滿像的 -對吧？
I sincerely apologize.
非常抱歉
As his supervisor, Prosecutor Himeno's conduct falls under my responsibility.
姬野檢察官會惹出那種事 是因為我的監督不周
It's not your fault.
這不是你的錯
Once you start seeking power, there's no turning back, is there?
一旦開始追求權力，就無法回頭了
It demands a significant commitment,
那需要相當的覺悟
but it seems that Himeno…
但姬野的覺悟啊
lacked it a little.
好像不太夠呢
It appears so.
看來是如此
Organizations are so terrifying.
“組織”還真是可怕啊
"The prosecution must uphold justice."
“檢察官一定要是正義的一方
"You must secure a conviction no matter what."
要不擇手段得到有罪的結果”
I've never said anything like that, though.
我從來都沒有講過那種話
Do I come across as that frightening?
我有這麼可怕嗎？
Regarding Attorney Akizumi,
原來你之前就認識
you knew of him.
明墨律師了啊
He's famous, after all.
他可是名人啊
He's good-looking too.
而且長相又帥氣
He's the type of person the media adores.
媒體最喜歡那種人了
But…
不過呢
he's a little…
他有一點…
His acquittal--
他獲判無罪…
Annoying, isn't he?
煩人呢
Pull over here.
請在這裡停車
I'll leave my stuff here, so wait a while for me.
我把行李放這裡，請等我一下
Sure.
好的
INDUSTRIAL WASTE INTERMEDIATE MANAGEMENT FACILITY
（事業廢棄物中間處理設施）
BRING YOUR WASTE
（可攜入垃圾）
Mr. Hiyama!
緋山先生！
Um,
請問一下
is that…
那是…
You knew the truth from the start.
你從一開始就知道所有真相了吧？
Mr. Hiyama committed a crime.
緋山先生有犯罪
He committed murder!
他有殺人！
Even though he was your client…
就算他是委託人
Did you have to go to such lengths to secure an acquittal?
有必要為了讓他被判無罪 做到那種地步嗎？
I struggle to understand
你對於正義的定義到底是什麼？
where your sense of justice lies.
我真的搞不懂
Justice…
正義…
huh?
是嗎？
What if…
這麼假設吧
your precious family
如果你重要的家人
had their lives threatened?
有生命危險，你會怎麼做？
Imagine this.
在你眼前
A man with a knife…
有一個男人拿著刀
is about to kill your precious family.
他即將殺害你珍愛的家人
And you…
而你手中…
have a knife capable of killing him.
正握著能殺掉那個男人的刀
What would you do, Akamine?
你會怎麼做？赤峰
Will you kill the man…
你會為了守護家人
to protect your family?
殺掉那個男人嗎？
Why do you ask?
為什麼要問那種事？
Just curious.
單純是因為好奇
I'll kill him.
我會下手殺了他
Someone compelled to kill
為了守護重要的對象
in order to save a loved one.
而逼不得已殺人的人
Someone who attempted…
跟懷抱著殺意
to kill another with malicious intent but failed.
企圖殺人卻沒成功的人
Whose crime carries greater weight?
哪一方的罪孽比較深重？
I wonder,
所謂的正義
what is justice?
究竟是什麼呢？
I respect your decision.
我會尊重你的意志
You should do as you like.
做你想做的事就好
However…
不過呢
just as you will stick to your sense of justice,
如同你會貫徹自己的正義
I will also follow my own path.
我也會在自己的道路上繼續前行
There's a letter for you.
有收到信
Says he wants to pay a visit.
似乎是請求會面
MASAKI AKIZUMI
（明墨正樹）
SHELTER DOGS NEWSLETTER
（《收容犬期刊》）
SAYA LOOKS CUTE IN THE PICTURE
（把紗耶拍得很可愛）
-Welcome back, Saya! -Hey!
-你回來啦，紗耶！ -我回來了！
It's good to be back.
-我回來囉 -今天要幹嘛？
Sure!
好啊！
CHILDREN'S HOME YUMEMIRAI
（兒童養護設施 夢想未來之家）
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：王姮婕
Your actions are no different from those of a criminal.
你所做的事情跟罪犯沒兩樣
They thrive on scandals involving politicians and their children.
最愛跟政客小孩有關的醜聞了
Are you doing this to pin guilt on an innocent person?
是為了將罪責歸咎於無辜之人？